Kids, I'm going to tell you an incredible story.
the story of how I met your mother.
Are we being punished for something?
No.
-Is this going to take a while?
-Yes.
25 years ago, before I was dad,
I had this whole other life.
It was way back to 2005.
I was 27，just starting to make it as an architect and living in New York with Marshal, my best friend from college.
My life was good, and then uncle Marshal went to screw the whole thing up.
Will you marry me?
Yes, perfect, and you're engaged.
You pop up the champagne. You drink a toast. You have sex on the kitchen floor.
Don't have sex on our kitchen floor.
Got it.
Thanks for helping me plan this out, Ted.
Are you kidding? It's you and Lily!
I've been there for all the big moment of you and Lily.
The night you met, your first date,
other first things.
Sorry, we thought you were asleep.
It's physics, Marshal. If the bottom bunk moves, the top bunk moves, too.
My God!
You're getting engaged tonight!
Yeah.
What are you doing tonight?
What was I doing?
Your uncle Marshal was taking the biggest step of his life. And me?
I'm calling up your uncle Barney.
Hey, see, you know, however, I thought I had a thing for half Asian girls?
Well, now I've got a new favourite,
Lebanese girls.
Lebanese girls are the new half Asians.
Hey, you want to do something tonight?
OK, meet me at the bar in 15 minutes,
and suit up!
Hey.
Where is your suit?
-Just once when I say 'suit up', I wish you'd put on a suit.
-I did, that one time.
It was a blazer.
You know, ever since college it's been Marshal and Lily and me.
Now it's going to be Marshal and Lily, and me.
They'll get married, start a family.
Before long I'm that weird, middle-aged bechalor, their kids call 'uncle Ted'.
I see what this is about.
Have you forgotten what I said to you the night we met?
Ted, I'm going to teach you how to live.
Barney. We met at the urinal.
Oh, alright.
Alright.
Lesson one, lose the goatee.
It doesn't go with your suit.
-I'm not wearing a suit.
-Lesson two, get a suit.
Suits are cool, exhibitive.
Lesson 3, don't even think about getting married till you're 30.
30, right, you're right.
I guess that just your best friends get engaged, you start thinking about that stuff.
I thought I was your best friend.
Ted, say I'm your best friend.
-You're my best friend, Barney.
-Good,
and as your best friend, I suggest we play a little game I'd like to call
-'have you met Ted'.
-No, we are not playing 'have you met Ted.'
Hi, have you met Ted?
Hi!
I'm Ted.
Yasmin.
It's a very pretty name.
Thanks. It's Lebanese.
I'm exhausted. It was finger painting day at school.
A 5-year-old boy got to second base with me.
Wow, are you cooking?
Yes, I am.
Are you sure that's a good idea
after last time you looked really creepy without eyebrows.
I can handle this. So think you'll find I'm full of surprise tonight.
So there's more surprises? Like what?
Marshal was in the second year of law school, so he was pretty good at thinking on his feet.
And that's all of them!
I'm going to go cook.
I'm so happy for Marshal. I really am. I just couldn't imagine settling down right now.
So do you think you'll ever get married?
Well, maybe eventually
Some fall day
possibly in Central Park
simple ceremony, we are better on vows.
band, no DJ, people will dance. I'm not going to worry about it.
Damn it! Why did Marshal have to get engaged!
Yeah, nothing hotter than a guy planning out his imaginary wedding.
Actually I think it's cute.
Well, you're clearly drunk.
One more for the lady.
Oh, hey, look what I got.
Oh, honey, champagne!
No, you're too old to be scared to open a bottle of champagne.
I'm not scared.
-Then open it.
-Fine.
Please open it.
You're unbelievalbe, Marshal ...
There are two big questions a man has to ask in life:
one you planned out for months, the other just slipps out when you're half drunk at some bar.
Will you marry me?
You want to go out sometime?
Of course, you idiot!
I'm sorry, Carl's my boyfriend.
What's up, Carl?
I promised Ted we wouldn't do that.
Did you know there is a pop under your fridge?
No, but dips.
Where's that champagne?
I want to drink a toast
with my fiancee.
Hard to know I was so scared at this.
It's pretty easy, right?
Why am I freaking out all of a sudden. This is crazy. I'm not ready to get settled down.
How does Carl lend a Lebanese girl?
-The plan's always been, don't even think about it until you're 30.
-Exactly.
The guy doesn't even own a suit.
Plus, Marshal's found the love of his life.
Even if I was ready, which I'm not,
but if I was, it's like,
'OK, I'm ready, where is she?'
And there she was.
It was like something from an old movie,
with a sailor sees the girl across the crowded dance floor, turns to his buddy, and says, 'see that girl?
I'm going to marry her some day.'
-Hey, Barney, See that girl?
-Oh, yeah, you just know that she likes dirty.
-Go say 'hi.'
-I can't just go say 'hi.'
I need a plan.
I'm going to wait until she goes to the bathroom.
I'll strategically place myself by the jukebox...
Hi, have you met Ted?
Let me guess, Ted?
Sorry, Lily, I'm so sorry.
Take us to the hospital.
Did you hit her?
Hit me? Please!
This guy can barely even spank me in bed for fun.
He's all like, 'Oh, honey, did that hurt?'
And I'm like, 'Oh, come on! Let me have you, pansy.'
Wow, complete stranger.
No, it's OK, go on.
So, these spankings, in pajamas or all natural?
So what do you do?
I'm a reporter from Metronews One.
Kind of a reporter.
I do those dumb little fluff pieces at the end of the news, you know, like,
monkey can play the ukulele.
I'm hoping to get some bigger stories soon.
Bigger like, gorilla with an upright bass?
I'm sorry. You're really pretty.
Oh, your friends don't seem too happy.
Yeah, see the one in the middle just got dumped by her boyfriend, so tonight,
every guy is the "enemy".
You know if it'll make your friend feel better, you could throw a drink in my face. I don't mind.
She would love that.
It does look fun in the movies.
Hey, you want to have dinner with me Saturday night?
Oh, I can't. I'm going to Orlando for a week on Friday.
Some guy's attempting to make the world's biggest pancake. Guess who's covering it?
-That's going to take a week?
-Yes. He's going to eat it, too. That's another record.
Hey, what's taking so long?
I know this is a long shot, but how about tomorrow night?
Yeah, what the hell?
Jerk!
That was fun.
De -- wait for it -- nied!
Denied!
We're going out tomorrow night.
I thought we were playing laser attack tomorrow night!
Yeah, I was never going to play laser attack.
The next night, I took her out to this little in Brooklyn.
Wow, that is one bad ass boof French horn.
Yeah, so it looks like a penis.
Son, a piece of advice.
When you go on a first date, you really don't want to say 'penis.'
Girls don't ordinarilly like that.
But this was no ordinary girl.
Lily?
How have you been sitting there?
The stupid odd patch!
Mom, dad, I have found the future Mrs. Ted Mosbie!
Marshal, how have I always described my perfect woman?
I'll let see.
She likes dogs?
I've got 5 dogs.
She drinks scotch?
I love a scotch that's old enough to own it's own scotch.
Can quote obsure lines from 'Ghost Busters?'
'Ray, when someone ask you if you're God, you say yes!'
And I'm saving the best for last.
Do you want this? I hate olives.
She hates olives! Awesome!
The olive theory!
The olive theory is based on my friends Marshal and Lily.
He hates olives. She loves them. And that makes them such a great couple.
Perfect balance.
You know, I've had a jar of olives just sitting in my fridge forever.
I can take them off your hands.
They are all yours.
Oh, it is on! It is on till that breakup done!
Wait, it's only the break at 10:30. What happened?
I've got to get one of those boof French horns over my fireplace.
It's got to be blue. It's got to be French.
No green clarinet?
No purple tuba?
It's a penis. We are no dice.
There you are.
We got a jumper, some crazy guy on the Manhattan Bridge.
Come on. You're covering it.
Alright, I'll be right there.
I'm sorry.
I had a really great time tonight.
Yeah.
So? Did you kiss her?
No, the moment wasn't right.
Look, this woman could actually be my future wife. I want our first kiss to be amazing.
Oh, Ted, that is so sweet!
So you chickened out like a little bitch.
What? I did not chicken out.
You know what? I don't need to take a first kiss advice from some pirate
who hasn't be single since the first week at college.
Ted, anyone who's single would tell you the same thing.
Even the dumbest single person alive.
And if you don't believe me? Call him.
Hey, loser? How's not playing laser attack? Because playing laser attack is awesome!
I killed you, connered. I'll make me get your mom.
Listen, I need your opinion on something.
OK, meet me at the bar in 15 minutes.
Suit up!
So these guys think I chickened out.
What do you think?
I can't believe
you're still not waring a suit!
She didn't even give me the signal.
What? Is she going to bat her eyes at you in Morse code?
'Ted, kiss me.'
No, you just kiss her!
Not if you don't get the signal.
-Did Marshal give me the signal?
-No!
I didn't. I swear.
At least tonight I get to sleep knowing Marshal and me, never going to happen.
You should have kissed her.
I should have kissed her.
Maybe in a week when she gets back from Orlando.
A week? That's like a year in hot girl's time.
She'll forget all about you.
Mark my words, you'll never see that one again.
There she is!
Woo, she's cute. Carl, turn it up.
... him to reconsider
at which point the man came down off the ledge, giving this bizzare story a happy ending.
Reporting from Metro 1 News ...
Didn't jump.
I'm going to kiss her.
Right now.
Dude, it's midnight. As your future lawyer I might advice you that's freaking crazy.
I never do anything crazy. I'm always waiting for the moment, planning the moment.
She's leaving tomorrow. This maybe the only chance I'm going to get.
I got to do what that guy couldn't. I got to take the leap.
OK, not a perfect metaphor.
Because for me it's falling in love and getting married and for him, it's
death.
Actually, that is a perfect metaphor.
By the way, could I congratulate you two?
I'm doing this.
Let's go.
-Where?
-We're coming with you.
Barney?
Alright. But under one condition.
Look at you, you beautiful bastard! You're suited up!
This is totally going in my block.
Stop the car. Pull over right here.
I got to do something.
Excuse me. Pardon me. Just say
enjoy your coffee.
Go, go, go!
Everybody brings flowers.
OK, the moment of truth.
Wish me luck.
Ted's going to get it on a with a TV reporter.
'It's just in.' OK...
Kiss her, Ted. Kiss her good!
Kiss the crap out of that girl!
Marshal, remember this night.
And you're the best man at our wedding. You give a speech. You're going to tell this story.
Why does he get to be the best man?
I'm your best friend!
As I walked up to that door, a million thoughts raised to my mind.
Unfortunately one particular thought did not.
I've got 5 dogs.
Not good, not good ...
-No!
-Get back in there!
You're wearing a suit!
Ted?
Hi!
I was just
come on up.
He's in.
So, Ranjit
You must have done that with a Lebanese girl.
OK, that's my Barney. Let me
I'm going to see if that has a bathroom.
Actually, I'm from Bangladesh.
The women hot there?
Here's a picture of my wife.
He'll know what he sufficed.
She's lovely.
So Ted, what brings you back to Brooklyn at 1 in the morning in a suit?
I was just hoping to
get those olives.
We shall have these olives with some gin and vermuth?
Are you trying to get me drunk?
We're starters.
So Marshal,
-This olive theory, based on you and Lily?
-Yeah.
You hate olives. Lily loves them. You can't stand them?
Yeah, I hate olives.
Two weeks ago, Spanish Bar at 79th Street, dish of olive, you had some.
What up!
You have to swear that this does not leave this cab.
I swear.
On our first date, I ordered a Greek salad. Lily asked if she could have my olives.
I said, 'sure, I hate olives.'
But you like olives.
Well, I was 18, OK? I was a virgin.
I've been waiting my whole life for a pretty girl to want my olives.
Marshal, I'm going to give you an early wedding present
Don't get married.
I think I like your olive theory.
I think I like your French horn.
I think I like your nose.
I think I'm in love with you.
What?
Come on, man! You said your stomach's been hurting, right? You know what that is.
Hunger. You're hungry for experience, hungry for something new,
hungry for olives.
But you're too scared to do anything about it.
Yeah, I'm scared, OK?
But I want to get to spending the rest of my life with Lily.
committing forever.
It doesn't scare me at all.
I'm marrying that girl.
Lily,
Lily, I like olives.
We'll make it work.
So Orlando, you're going to hit this new world?
You love me?
I can't believe I said that.
Why did I say that?
Who says that?
I should just go.
Hold on. Wait a minute.
I promised these.
-Olives.
-Yes.
Thanks. I love you.
What is wrong with me!
Why we are still sitting here?
Let' go. We can still make a last call.
What do you say，Lil？
Yuhoho, and a bottle of rum!
Because you're a pirate?
OK, I patch gone.
We can't just abandon Ted.
If it doesn't go well up there, he's going to need some support.
It's been, like, 20 minutes.
You think they're doing it?
-You think they're doing it in front of the dogs?
-Doggy style?
There is a girl in college who had this golden retriever ...
OK, we can go to the bar. Just stop talking.
Hit it, Ranjie.
So when you tell this to your friends,
could you avoid the word, 'psycho?'
I'd prefer 'eccentric.'
Good night, psycho.
Great.
How do we get the train?
Two blocks. That way and take a right.
You know what?
I'm done being single.
I'm not good at it.
Obviously, you can't tell a woman you just met you love her.
But
it sucks that you can't.
I'll tell you something new, if a woman
not you, just some hypothetical woman
would bear with me through all this,
I think I'd make a damn good husband.
Because that's the stuff I'd be good at,
stuff like, making her laugh and being a good father
and her 5 hypothetical dogs,
and being a good kisser.
Everyone thinks he's a good kisser.
I've got references.
Good night, Ted.
And I'm a good handshaker.
That's a pretty good handshake.
And that was it. I'll never see her again.
What?
That was the signal!
That long, lingering handshake! You should have kissed her!
There's no such thing as the signal.
But yeah, that was the signal.
Signal.
Carl, thank you.
Something I got to do?
By the way,
you should have kissed her.
Carl, you guys weren't there!
I am so turned on right now.
Guys, trust me! I've seen the signal.
That was not the signal!
Yeah, Ted, we're not on your anymore.
To my fiancee.
To the future.
To one the hell of a night.
That was not the signal!
I asked her about it years later
and yeah, that was the signal.
I could have kissed her.
But that's the funny thing about destiny.
It happens whether you plan it or not.
I mean I never thought I'd see that girl again.
But it turns out I was just too close to the puzzle to see the picture that was formal.
Bacause that, kids, is the true story
of how I met your aunt Robin.
Aunt Robin?
I thought this was how you met mom.
Will you relax? I'm getting to it.
Like I said, it's a long story.